Guide to the Records of Amnesty International of the USA, Inc.
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series IX: Communications Department/Media Relations Files, 1973-1997
  - Subseries IX.7: Newspaper Clippings, 1981-1997
    - Topics, 1981 1984 1988 1992-1997
      - Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation Summit, 1994 (Box Box 377, Folder 58)
      - Blind Melon Tour, 1994 (Box Box 377, Folder 59)
      - Board of directors, 1993 (Box Box 377, Folder 60)
      - Business and human rights, 1996 (Box Box 377, Folder 61)
      - Campaign on Extra-Judicial Executions/Disappearances, 1993 (Box Box 377, Folder 62)
      - Celebrities, 1993 (Box Box 377, Folder 63)
      - Children, 1994-1996 (Box Box 377, Folder 64)
      - Death penalty
        - 1993-1994, (2 folders) (Box Box 377, Folder 65-66)
        - 1995-1996, (2 folders) (Box Box 378, Folder 1-2)
      - Elections and Campaigns, 1996 (Box Box 378, Folder 3)
      - European Union, 1996 (Box Box 378, Folder 4)
      - Events, personalities, concerts, benefits, 1994 -1996, (3 folders) (Box Box 378, Folder 5-7)
      - Fundraising, 1993 (Box Box 378, Folder 8)
      - Gay/Lesbian Rights and Campaigns, 1993-1996, (4 folders) (Box Box 378, Folder 9-12)
      - General, 1993 (Box Box 378, Folder 13-16)
      - Groups, membership, volunteers, 1994-1996, (3 folders) (Box Box 378, Folder 17-19)
      - Human Rights, 1994-1996, (3 folders) (Box Box 378, Folder 20-22)
      - Human Rights Day, groups, write-a-thon, 1993 (Box Box 378, Folder 23)
      - Human rights--United States security assistance, 1994 (Box Box 378, Folder 24)
      - Immigration, 1996 (Box Box 378, Folder 25)
      - Indigenous people, 1992-1996 (Box Box 378, Folder 26)
      - International Criminal Court, 1996 (Box Box 378, Folder 27)
      - Iqbal Masih, 1995 (Box Box 378, Folder 28)
      - Junk mail/funding abuses, 1994 (Box Box 378, Folder 29)
      - Kurds, 1994-1995 (Box Box 378, Folder 30)
      - Memorials, 1993-1996 (Box Box 378, Folder 31)
      - Miami summit of the Americas, 1994 (Box Box 378, Folder 32)
      - "Miscellaneous Information," 1995-1996, (2 folders) (Box Box 378, Folder 33-34)
      - Mississippi jail suicides, 1993 (Box Box 378, Folder 35)
      - Movies, concerts and special events, 1993 (Box Box 380, Folder 1)
      - Moving the Mountain (Documentary Film), 1995 (Box Box 380, Folder 2)
      - "MSP-HR and U.S. Security Assistance," 1996 (Box Box 380, Folder 3)
      - Nasrin, Taslima, 1995 (Box Box 380, Folder 4)
      - NATO, 1996 (Box Box 380, Folder 5)
      - New York Police Department brutality, 1996 (Box Box 380, Folder 6)
      - Nobel Prize, 1977 (Box Box 380, Folder 7)
      - Oklahoma State Penitentiary, H-Unit, 1994-1995 (Box Box 380, Folder 8)
      - Olympics, 1996 (Box Box 380, Folder 9)
      - Police brutality, 1996 (Box Box 380, Folder 10)
      - Policy, 1993 (Box Box 380, Folder 11)
      - Public service announcements, 1995 (Box Box 380, Folder 12)
      - Rape, 1996 (Box Box 380, Folder 13)
      - Refugees, 1993-1994 1996, (2 folders) (Box Box 380, Folder 14-15)
      - Religion, 1996 (Box Box 380, Folder 16)
      - Sagan, Ginetta and Fund, 1996 (Box Box 380, Folder 17)
      - Slavery, 1996 (Box Box 380, Folder 18)
      - Spanish language, 1996-1997 (Box Box 380, Folder 19)
      - Students, 1993-1996, (3 folders) (Box Box 380, Folder 20-22)
      - Stun technology, 1996 (Box Box 380, Folder 23)
      - Third world labor, 1996 (Box Box 380, Folder 24)
      - Torture, 1993-1994 1996, (3 folders) (Box Box 380, Folder 25-27)
      - United Nations, 1993-1996 (Box Box 380, Folder 28)
      - Urgent Action, 1986-1988 (Box Box 380, Folder 29)
      - Web sites, 1996 (Box Box 380, Folder 30)
      - Women
        - Beijing Conference, 1995 (Box Box 380, Folder 31)
        - Issues, 1993 (Box Box 380, Folder 32)
        - Rights, 1994-1996, (3 folders) (Box Box 380, Folder 33-35)
      - World Conference, 1993 (Box Box 380, Folder 36)
      - Wu, Harry (Box Box 380, Folder 37)
    - Topics--1998 Accession, 1987-1996 (Box "1092")
      - Best Clips, 1987-1989, (3 Folders) (Box "1092", Folder 6-8)
      - Bill Schulz, 1994 (Box "1092", Folder 3)
      - Current Op/Eds and Responses, 1991-1993 (Box "1092", Folder 2)
      - Latino/Spanish Press Lists, 1995 (Box "1092", Folder 15)
      - New York Times--Story/Letters, 1995 July 26 (Box "1092", Folder 12)
        (This is related to the accuracy of AI’s research work and reports)
      - Op/Ed: Curt: Bahrain--Wall Street Journal, 1995 June 12 (Box "1092", Folder 13)
      - Press Clippings (Western Region?), 1987-1988 (Box "1092", Folder 11)
      - Press Clippings on Campaigns in Cambodia, Guatemala, and Iran, 1987 May-July (Box "1092", Folder 10)
      - Press Clippings--Subject Indexes, 1990 July-September (Box "1092", Folder 9)
      - Roger’s/Anne’s Return, 1994-1996 (Box "1092", Folder 4)
      - United States: Police Brutality and Excessive Force in the New York City Police Department--Press Clips Mailing (AI Index: AMR 51/36/96), 1996 June (Box "1092", Folder 16)
      - University of Colorado at Boulder--Report on Human Rights Collections, 1996 August 1 (Box "1092", Folder 14)
      - Utah Coverage, 1996 January 25 (Box "1092", Folder 17)
        (Coverage of execution by firing squad)
      - WC Press Clips, 1993 (Box "1092", Folder 1)
        (Clippings on the United Nations world conference on human rights)
      - Western Region: Press Clips, 1994-1995 (Box "1092", Folder 5)
  - Subseries IX.8: AIUSA News Releases, 1986-1996
    The subseries contains news releases issued by Amnesty International USA. The news releases are arranged chronologically through 1995. Many news releases are also filed individually after June 1995. Most files consist only of news releases, but some files also contain related reports, letters, and policy statements on media issues.
    - Chronological Files (Box 380)
      - 1986, 1989, 1991, 1993, (5 Folders) (Box 380, Folder 38-41)
      - 1994 January-August, (10 Folders) (Box 380, Folder 42-51)
      - 1994 September-1995 September, (15 Folders) (Box 381, Folder 1-13)
    - Files for Individual Press Releases, 1995 July-1996
      - United States Police Brutality Widespread Problem in New York City, 1996 June 27 (Box "1091", Folder 1)
        (Includes AI report on)
      - International Community Failing to Take Responsibility for Massive Human Rights Violations in 1995 (Annual Report Release), 1996 June 18 (Box "1091", Folder 2)
      - Annual Report (ANRP96) Summary and Update, 1996 June 18 (Box "1091", Folder 3)
      - New York Police Report Press Conference Media Advisory, 1996 June 26 (Box "1091", Folder 4)
      - United States from Annual Report (ANRP96), 1996 (Box "1091", Folder 5)
        (Copy of USA entry only)
      - Stun Tech “React” Belt System Information Pack, 1996 June 10 (Box "1091", Folder 6)
        (No press release)
      - 27 Companies (“Arms Trading”), 1996 June 14 (Box "1091", Folder 7)
        (List of possible manufacturers)
      - Stun Tech, 1996 (Box "1091", Folder 8)
        (Background material)
      - Zaire AFR 62/29/96 1996 December (Box "1091", Folder 9)
      - Turkey: Widespread Human Rights Violations, 1996 October 1 (Box "1091", Folder 10)
        (Includes the report, Turkey: No Security Without Human Rights, and the briefing on the report)
      - “Group: Columbia Aid Diverted,” 1996 October 30 (Box "1091", Folder 11)
      - Organize for Change-Challenge Institutionalized Oppression (PSA), 1996 October 24 (Box "1091", Folder 12)
      - Press Conference: United States Funded Human Rights Violators in Columbia--Remarks: B. Schulz, 1996 October 29 (Box "1091", Folder 13)
      - Leaked Documents Point to United States Weapons Meant for Drug War Used to Kill Innocent People in Columbia--AIUSA Calls for Ban on Arms Transfer to Columbia, 1996 October 29 (Box "1091", Folder 14)
      - Talking Points: Ogoni 9 One Year Anniversary and Amnesty SLA, 1996 October 22 (Box "1091", Folder 15)
      - United States: Georgia to Execute E.W. Felker Despite Grave Doubts Concerning His Guilt, 1996 November 13 (Box "1091", Folder 16)
      - Texas and Virginia Schedule Executions for International Human Rights Day, 1996 December 3 (Box "1091", Folder 17)
      - Palestinian Authority: Human Rights Guarantees Should Be Implemented Without Delay, 1996 December 2 (Box "1091", Folder 18)
      - AIUSA Welcomes Stay in O’Dell Case, 1996 December 17 (Box "1091", Folder 19)
      - Bosnia-Herzegovina: One Year After Srebrenica, 1996 July 3 (Box "1091", Folder 20)
      - AI Press Conference in Atlanta During 1996 Olympic Games…, 1996 July 9 (Box "1091", Folder 21)
        (Release of report on the death penalty in Georgia)
      - United States: Death Penalty in the Olympic State: Racist, Arbitrary, and Unfair, 1996 July 23 (Box "1091", Folder 22)
      - Human Rights Under the Palestinian Authority: AI Testimony by M. Elahi, 1996 July 23 (Box "1091", Folder 23)
        (Before the US House Committee on International Operations and Human Rights)
      - Egypt, 1996 July 3 (Box "1091", Folder 24)
        (AI Index: MDE 12/13/96 Document on Indefinite Detention and Torture)
      - Clinton Puts Yeltsin Re-Election Ahead of Human Rights, 1996 July 18 (Box "1091", Folder 25)
      - Grapes of Wrath, 1996 July 24 (Box "1091", Folder 26)
        (On military operation in Lebanon)
      - Israel/Lebanon: AIUSA Calls on United States Government to Investigate Possible Use of US Weapons…in Lebanon, 1996 July 24 (Box "1091", Folder 27)
      - (Spanish Language) Annual Report (ANRP) Release, 1996 June 26 (Box "1091", Folder 28)
      - National Black Police Association (NBPA) Supports AI Report, 1996 June 19 (Box "1091", Folder 29)
      - Radio for Peace Proposal, 1996 September (Box "1091", Folder 30)
      - Police Brutality in New York City--Statement by David Marshall, 1996 June 27 (Box "1091", Folder 31)
      - United States: Electro-Shock Stun Belts--Torture at the Push of a Button, 1996 June 12 (Box "1091", Folder 32)
      - United States: Use of Electro-Shock Stun Belts (AMR 61/45/96), 1996 June 12 (Box "1091", Folder 33)
        (AI Document)
      - Sri Lanka: Human Rights Situation at Critical Juncture, 1996 August 13 (Box "1091", Folder 34)
      - AI San Diego Group 137 Participates…in National Convention, 1996 August 11 (Box "1091", Folder 35)
      - President Clinton Awards “Medal of Freedom” to AI Activist Ginetta Sagan, 1996 September 9 (Box "1091", Folder 36)
      - AI Delegation Visits Turkey to Meet Government and to Launch Campaign on Turkey, 1996 September 24 (Box "1091", Folder 37)
      - Turkey: AI Delegation Visits Turkey to Meet Government, 1996 September 24 (Box "1091", Folder 38)
      - Update on Turkey Campaign, 1996 October 1 (Box "1091", Folder 39)
      - Human Rights and United States Security Assistance, 1996 May 23 (Box "1091", Folder 45)
      - 1995 Annual Report (ANRP), 1995 July 6 (Box "1091", Folder 46)
        (Includes Annual Report Summary and Selected Country Updates)
      - Nigeria: Ken Saro-Wiwa--Miscellaneous, 1995 November 10 (Box "1091", Folder 47)
      - Patrick Stewart Donates Funds for Human Rights Internships for College Students, Undated (Box "1091", Folder 48)
      - AIUSA Seeks Clemency in the Case of John Taylor (Utah), 1996 January 24 (Box "1091", Folder 49)
      - M Herskovitz--PSAs for AIUSA, 1996 February 23 (Box "1091", Folder 50)
      - International Women’s Day, 1996 March 8 (Box "1091", Folder 51)
      - China: World Can No Longer Ignore Human Rights of 1.2 Billion People, 1996 March 13, (2 Folders) (Box "1091", Folder 52-52A)
        (Includes AI briefing and AI report,China: No One is Safe )
      - AI to Launch Campaign Against Human Rights Abuses in China, 1996 March 12 (Box "1091", Folder 53)
      - Patrick Stewart Donates Funds, 1995 November 9 (Box "1091", Folder 54)
      - Turkey: AI Calls for Halt to Helicopter Transfers, 1996 January 14 (Box "1091", Folder 55)
      - Turkey: 6 Deaths in Custody in 10 Days--AI Sends Delegation to Investigate, 1996 January 11 (Box "1091", Folder 56)
      - AIUSA Challenges Presidential Candidates on United States Policy, 1996 March 13 (Box "1091", Folder 57)
      - China: No One is Safe--Press Conference Statement: Curt Goering, 1996 March 13 (Box "1091", Folder 58)
      - Owens Wiwa--Environmental Media Services (Nigeria), 1996 January 30 (Box "1091", Folder 59)
      - Shell in Nigeria, 1995 December 21 (Box "1091", Folder 60)
        (Shell Oil)
      - Wei Jingsheng (China), 1995 December 13 (Box "1091", Folder 61)
      - Why Black Americans Should Care About Politics Around the World, 1995 November (Box "1091", Folder 62)
        (by Gerald LeMelle)
      - December 10 Talking Points, 1995 November 29 (Box "1091", Folder 63)
      - The Truth in Nigeria Ad, 1995 December 6 (Box "1091", Folder 64)
      - AIUSA Condemns Disinformation in International Print Ads on Nigeria, 1995 December 6 (Box "1091", Folder 65)
      - Pakistan: Women’s Rights, 1995 December 5 (Box "1091", Folder f, 66)
        (Includes AI Report,Women in Pakistan: Disadvantaged and Denied their Rights )
      - Where is the Child?, 1995 December 1 (Box "1091", Folder 67)
        (On disappearance of the 11th Panchen Lama)
      - Media Advisory on Schulz Speech for Human Rights Day--Cleveland, 1995 December 1 (Box "1091", Folder 68)
      - Afghanistan, 1995 November 28 (Box "1091", Folder 69)
        (Includes AI report, Afghanistan: International Responsibility for Human Rights Disaster, and AI briefing,Afganistan: The World’s Responsibility )
      - Media Advisory (MA) on Clinton Bosnia Address, 1995 November 27 (Box "1091", Folder 70)
      - Danger Areas of the Bosnia-Herzegovina Peace Accord, 1995 November 22 (Box "1091", Folder 71)
      - Wei Jingsheng Charged with Treason; Could Face Death Sentence (China), 1995 November 21 (Box "1091", Folder 72)
      - No Peace Without Justice, 1995 November 21 (Box "1091", Folder 73)
        (Opinion submission to the New York Times on the formation of an international criminal court)
      - Mexico: AI Report on the Human Rights Situation, 1995 November 15 (Box "1091", Folder 74)
      - Mexico: Spanish Language Release, 1995 November 15 (Box "1091", Folder 75)
      - AI Opposes…One Child Policy (China), 1995 November 17 (Box "1091", Folder 76)
      - Sri Lanka Testimony, 1995 November 15 (Box "1091", Folder 77)
        (Before the House Committee on International Relations)
      - Asian-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC), 1995 November 15 (Box "1091", Folder 78)
      - Bosnia-Herzegovina Statement by Jim O’Dea, 1995 November 15 (Box "1091", Folder 79)
        (Statement to the United States House Committee on International Relations)
      - Tunisia, 1995 November 2 (Box "1091", Folder 80)
        (Includes country report)
      - AIUSA Expresses Shock and Outrage at Killings of Nigerian Activists, 1995 November 2 (Box "1091", Folder 81)
      - Media Advisory: Bosnia Testimony/Nigeria, Kenya Briefing, 1995 November 15 (Box "1091", Folder 82)
      - Model Fax to Shell Oil Company Re: Nigeria/Ken Saro-Wiwa, 1995 November 10 (Box "1091", Folder 83)
      - Update on Saro-Wiwa Sentencing, 1995 November 8 (Box "1091", Folder 84)
      - Shell Oil Company Called to Task for Human Rights Abuses in Nigeria’s Ogoni Region, 1995 October 25 (Box "1091", Folder 85)
      - AIUSA Welcomes New Executives--Roughs, 1995 October 23 (Box "1091", Folder 86)
        (LeMelle and Rackley)
      - Israel and the Occupied Territories: AI Condemns New Draft Law Effectively Legalizing Torture, 1995 October 22 (Box "1091", Folder 87)
      - United Nations: AI Urges World Leaders…to Establish International Criminal Court (ICC), 1995 October 19 (Box "1091", Folder 88)
      - Press Statement/OpEd--Nigeria/Kenya Campaign, 1995 October (Box "1091", Folder 89)
      - Ken Saro-Wiwa Execution Confirmation (Nigeria), 1995 November 8 (Box "1091", Folder 90)
      - AIUSA: Ken Saro-Wiwa Statement (Nigeria), 1995 October 31 (Box "1091", Folder 91)
      - Kenya and Nigeria: Freedom in the Balance--AI Testimony, 1995 November 15 (Box "1091", Folder 92)
        (Testimony before the US House Human Rights Caucus)
      - Nigeria: Travesty of Justice, 1995 October 26 (Box "1091", Folder 93)
        (Report only)
      - AIUSA Welcomes New Executives: G LeMelle and L Rackley Join…, 1995 October 23 (Box "1091", Folder 94)
      - Statement on Launch of “Freedom in the Balance”, 1995 October 19 (Box "1091", Folder 95)
        (Campaign on Kenya and Nigeria)
      - Freedom in the Balance, 1995 October 12 (Box "1091", Folder 96)
      - Nigeria/Kenya Packets, 1995 August 3 (Box "1091", Folder 97)
      - Press Invitation: Nigeria/Kenya Campaign, 1995 October 6 (Box "1091", Folder 98)
      - Rwanda: Stop Arms Flow to Perpetrators of Genocide, 1995 June 12 (Box "1091", Folder 99)
      - Mort Winston, 1995 October 10 (Box "1091", Folder 100)
        (Election as Chair of the Board of Directors)
      - Death Penalty Promotes Violent Society…Says AI, 1995 October 4 (Box "1091", Folder 101)
      - Death Penalty Not a Solution to Drug Trafficking, 1995 October 2 (Box "1091", Folder 102)
        (Includes International Secretariat paper of same title)
      - “Disappeared” in Yugoslavia, 1995 October 2 (Box "1091", Folder 103)
        (Includes AI briefing on subject)
      - Egypt: AI Calls for Prompt …Investigations into All..Torture and Deaths in Custody, 1995 October 9 (Box "1091", Folder 104)
      - Middle East: Women’s Rights Under Attack, 1995 August 1 (Box "1091", Folder 105)
      - China’s “Public Order” Executions Condemned by AI, 1995 August 16 (Box "1091", Folder 106)
      - AIUSA Welcomes Wu’s Release, Says Clinton Should Meet (China), 1995 August 24 (Box "1091", Folder 107)
      - AIUSA Requests Clemency for Donald Stockton (Virginia), 1995 September 25 (Box "1091", Folder 108)
      - Op-Ed to New York Times (NYT)--Beijing/Women, 1995 August (Box "1091", Folder 109)
      - AI Asks First Lady Clinton to Speak Out for Women’s Rights in Beijing, 1995 September 1 (Box "1091", Folder 110)
      - AI Announces Release of Annual Report (ANRD), 1995 July 1 (Box "1091", Folder 111)
      - Spanish Annual Report News Release, 1995 July 6 (Box "1091", Folder 112)
      - Mass Human Rights Violations Mark 1994 AI Annual Report Details Human Rights Violations in 151 Countries, 1995 July 1 (Box "1091", Folder 113)
        (Includes copies of Annual Report Summary and Country Updates)
      - AIUSA Questions Clinton on Lifting Ban on Military Technology to China, 1995 July 12 (Box "1091", Folder 114)
        (Includes Urgent Action Appeal for Harry Wu)
      - Kenya: Government Image Conceals Human Rights Abuse, 1995 July 24 (Box "1091", Folder 115)
        (Includes report on Women in Kenya)
      - Statement of AIUSA on United Nations Conference on Women, 1995 July 25 (Box "1091", Folder 116)
    - AI Media Issues--General, 1995-1996 (Box "1095")
      - Policy on Release of AI Information to the Media (ACT 81/01/96), 1995 July 15 (Box "1095", Folder 40)
      - Media Work on Own Country (ACT 81/02/96), 1996 July (Box "1095", Folder 41)
      - Report of AIUSA-IS Relations Committee (ORG 41/06/96), 1996 July (Box "1095", Folder 42)
      - Media Issues Paper (IS-AIUSA), 1996 April (Box "1095", Folder 43)
      - Department Retreat Agenda, 1996 September 12 (Box "1095", Folder 44)
        (Communications Department)
  - Subseries IX.9: AI News Service, 1992-1997
    This series contains cover pages, news items, news releases, and general communications for press officers received from the Press Office of the International Secretariat (IS) in London. The files are arranged chronologically.
    - 1992-1994 (Box "1095", Folder 14)
    - 1995 January-1996 December, (19 Folders) (Box "1095", Folder 15-33)
    - 1997 January-March, (3 Folders) (Box 382, Folder 1-3)
  - Subseries IX.10: Roger Rathman Files, 1988, 1991-1995
    Rathman became the National Press Officer of Amnesty International USA in early 1993. Prior to this, he worked in a similar capacity for the organization in Los Angeles. The series includes files on campaigns, countries, issues, publicity efforts, and other subjects.
    - Amnesty in Print (#11 April 1993) (Box 382, Folder 4)
      (a selection of recent Canadian news articles)
    - AI Offices Worldwide--list of, 1993 March (Box 382, Folder 5)
    - AI Policy, 1991-1993, (2 Folders) (Box 382, Folder 6-7)
    - AI Press Awards, 1995 (Box 382, Folder 8)
      (British Section)
    - AI Publicity File, 1991 (Box 382, Folder 9)
      (This is an information packet)
    - Annual Reports, 1992-1993, (2 Folders) (Box 382, Folder 10-11)
      (resources, updates, etc.)
    - "Americas Summit" (Miami, FL), 1994 December 9-10 (Box 382, Folder 12)
    - Annual General Meeting (AGM), 1993 (Box 382, Folder 13)
    - Blind Melon Tour, 1994 (Box 382, Folder 14)
    - Breaking the Silence--book award State University of New York (SUNY), 1994 (Box 382, Folder 15)
    - Country Campaigns and Country Files
      - Africa
        - Chad Campaign, 1993 (Box 382, Folder 16)
        - South Africa
          - Section-Level Action, 1992 (Box 382, Folder 17)
          - 1994 (Box 382, Folder 18)
      - Americas
        - Chile--“Human Rights: For the world’s prisoners of conscience, Amnesty International is a beacon of hope,” by Christopher Odgen in Time, 1988 October 17 (Box 382, Folder 19)
        - Haiti, 1994 (Box 382, Folder 20)
        - Mexico--Chiapas--AIUSA info packet, 1994 (Box 382, Folder 21)
        - United States
          - AI Report/Press Conference Re: Beating of Rodney King, 1992 (Box 382, Folder 22)
            (includes newspaper clippings)
          - Human Rights Concerns, 1992 (Box 382, Folder 23)
          - "U.S. News Media Coverage of International Human Rights," by Anne E. Geyer, 1988 May (Box 382, Folder 24)
      - Asia
        - China
          - Tibet Campaign, 1992 (Box 382, Folder 25)
          - 1993 (Box 382, Folder 26)
        - India Campaign, 1992 (Box 382, Folder 27)
        - Indonesia Campaign--draft media strategy, Undated (Box 382, Folder 28)
        - Singapore--caning of Michael Fay, 1994 (Box 382, Folder 29)
      - Middle East and North Africa
        - Israel and Occupied Territories, 1994 (Box 382, Folder 30)
    - Co-Groups--lists of, and cases by country, 1992-1993 (Box 382, Folder 31)
    - Contract with the world, 1995 (Box 382, Folder 32)
    - Cotton, Stan--Marketing of A.I. products, 1993 (Box 382, Folder 33)
    - Current Controversy and AI, 1992-1993 (Box 382, Folder 34)
      (questions re objectivity concerning Israel, Toni Moore lawsuit, etc)
    - Death Penalty
      - Death penalty and drug offenders, 1990 (Box 382, Folder 35)
      - "Various/general info"--reports from various sources (Box 382, Folder 36)
      - 1995 (Box 382, Folder 37)
    - Disappearances and Political Killings Campaign, 1993, (2 Folders) (Box 382, Folder 38-39)
    - Freedberg, Jean, 1992-1993 (Box 382, Folder 40)
    - Free to Laugh: A Comedy and Music Special for AI, 1992 (Box 382, Folder 41)
    - Indigenous Peoples Campaign, 1992 (Box 382, Folder 42)
    - Kovalyou, Sergei Adamovich (USSR), 1995 (Box 382, Folder 43)
    - Monthly-minder, 1994 (Box 382, Folder 44)
    - News releases--revised guidelines for, 1991 (Box 384, Folder 1)
    - New York High School Cluster, 1993 (Box 384, Folder 2)
    - Roll Call: The Newspaper of Capitol Hill --Letter to the Editor of, 1994 June 10 (Box 384, Folder 3)
    - Unit meetings, 1993, (2 Folders) (Box 384, Folder 4-5)
    - United Nations
      - High Commissioner For Human Rights--A.I. reports on, 1990-1993 (Box 384, Folder 6)
      - World Conference on Human Rights (Vienna), 1993, (2 Folders) (Box 384, Folder 7-8)
    - Women